SAYED BIN TAHER

Software Engineer

 J+880 1849250564

Dhaka, Bangladesh

sayedbintaher.netlify.app



ABOUT ME

I am an innovative and hard-working software engineer with one year of software development experience. Looking for new opportunities to grow and enhance my skills, eventually following an aspiration to be an innovative and hardworking software engineer. Flexible with my work, changing technological stack, if necessary, would not be a problem.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Computer Science BRAC University

May, 2018 - Jan, 2022

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer TechnoNext Ltd.

July, 2023 - Current

- Utilized advanced accounting software, ShopLover Accounting, to manage financial transactions and generate comprehensive reports in the Accounting project.
- Played a key role in tracking and managing land assets, including land asset purchase and sales in the US Bangla Real Estate business project.
- Worked with different DBMS like MS SQL server and PostgreSQL, and aslo worked with popular ORM, Dapper to improve performance of overall application.

Junior Software Engineer Raven Systems Ltd.

March, 2023 - July, 2023

- involved in creation of an ASP .Net Core MVC application for Directorate of Inspection of Factories and Establishment(DIFE) following Layer Architecture where I contributed about 50% of the backend application.
- Contributed in the in house ERP system by including a small module for Support Ticket System.

Trainee Software Engineer eGeneration Ltd.

May, 2022 - December, 2022

- I completed training on ASP.NET Core MVC, Web API, and Entity Framework with a score of 75%, while following the Layered Architecture Pattern.
- Involved in creation of in-house Human Resource Management System where I contributed about 15% of the total work done in React.js.
- Generated multiple complex forms for Admin Module with frontend technology like Angular.

SKILLS

C# Asp .Net Core Entity Framework	Dapper
MS SQL PosgreSQL	
Angular Kendo UI Bootsrap	
VS Code Git Visual Studio Trello Re	edmine
PgAdmin SSMS	

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Course Management System

- Developed using Asp.Net Core MVC project
- Language: HTML, CSS, Razor Pages
- Tools: VS Code, MS SQL
- Project Link : Course Management System

Point of Sales

- Developed simple POS App Web API
- Language: Asp .Net Core, Entity Framework
- Tools: VS Code, MS SQL
- Project Link : Point of Sales

Product Management System

- Developed simple Asp .Net Web Api and Angular 15
- Language: Asp .NET Core, Angular, EF Core
- Tools: VS Code, MS SQL
- Project Link: Product Management System

RESEARCH

Analysis on the effects of wallstreetbets on the stock market

 We ran sentiment analysis on the Reddit's posts dataset and then used machine learning algorithms like KNN, Naive Bayes, and Random Forest for analysis. The results were gathered together to do a voting ensemble to make the final prediction.